ibisworld.com 2019-12-10

# Privacy Policy - IBISWorld

### PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT

This Privacy Policy explains how IBISWorld Pty Ltd. and its Affiliates (collectively "IBISWorld" “we” or “us”) may collect, use, manage and safeguard personal information through [www.ibisworld.com.au](https://www.ibisworld.com.au/), [www.ibisworld.co.uk](https://www.ibisworld.co.uk/), [www.ibisworld.com](https://www.ibisworld.com/), [www.procuremtentiq.com](https://www.procuremtentiq.com/), [www.ibisworld.ca](https://www.ibisworld.ca/), [www.ibisworld.co.nz](https://www.ibisworld.co.nz/), [https://clients1.ibisworld.com](https://clients1.ibisworld.com/), <https://client.procurementiq.com/procurement/>, applications, and any other services provided by us (the “Services”). 

We follow principles in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (the "GDPR") and worldwide practices for customer privacy and data protection. 

### INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND THE REASON FOR THE COLLECTION

We do not collect more information than we need to fulfil the stated purposes listed below. And we will only use the information for that purpose. 

#### Types of Information We Collect:

**Personal Data:** We may collect information that identifies you (“Personal Data”). It does not include data where the identity has been removed (this is anonymous data). The types of Personal Data we may collect includes: 

Identity Data: name   
Contact Data: email address, billing address, telephone number, company title   
Financial Data: credit card data or other financial account information   
Technical Data: internet protocol (IP) address, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access our websites   
Usage Data: information about how you use our products, services and website   
Marketing and Communications Data: your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences   

**Sensitive Data:** We **will not** collect, and do not want you to provide, any Sensitive Data revealing your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership. We will not process any genetic data, biometric data, data concerning your medical or health condition and data concerning your sexual orientation. 

#### Use of Data & Reason for Collection:

_Purpose/Activity_ | _Type of Personal Data_ | _Legal basis we rely on,  
including our   
legitimate interest (if   
applicable)_ | _Our legitimate  
interests (if applicable)_  
---|---|---|---  
Registering you as a new customer  | Identity Data, Contact Data, Financial Information | Performance of a contract with you  | To register you so can use the Service. And so you can pay for Service.  
Communicating with you when you submit inquires  | Identity Data, Contact Data | Consent, Our legitimate interests | To respond to your inquiries submitted through email or through social media platforms such as Twitter. And other customer service purposes.  
Providing the Service to you and managing your account  | Identity Data, Contact Data, Transaction Data | Performance of a Contract, Our legitimate interests | So we can better understand how you access and use the Service in order to improve the IBISWorld websites and Service. To respond to your requests and preferences, and for other research and analytical purposes.  
To send you newsletters, special offers, services, events or promotions or to contact you about products or information we think may interest you | Identity Data, Contact Data, Marketing and Communications Data | Consent, Our legitimate interests |   
To respond to the proper authorities in accordance with applicable laws or regulations to which we are subject, court orders, audits etc. | Identity Data, Contract Data, Financial Information; | Legal obligations |   
Fulfilling service orders requested by you | Identity Data, Contract Data, Financial Information | Performance of a Contract, Our legitimate interests,  |   
Communicating with you in regards technical issues relating to the Service | Identity Data, Contract Data  | Performance of a Contract with you, Our legitimate interests,  | To diagnose and relay information regarding technical problems.  
Submitting surveys about the Service | Identity Data, Contact Data | Our legitimate interests, Consent | When you respond to surveys for research purposes so we can improve our Service.  
Registering you for marketing events hosted by us | Identity Data, Contact Data; Marketing and Communications Data | Our legitimate interests, Consent  | To register you to attend an event regarding the Service we offer and for networking events such as conferences.   
To administer and protect our business and our website | Usage Data   
Technical Data | Performance of a contract with you,   
Our legitimate interests | Being efficient about how we fulfil our legal and contractual duties.  
Using data analytics to improve our website, services, marketing, client relationships and experiences | Usage Data | Performance of a contract with you, Our legitimate interests | Being efficient about how we fulfil our legal and contractual duties.  
To manage payments and collect and recover money that is owed to us | Identity Data  
Contact Data  
Transaction Data  
Financial Data  | Performance of a contract with you,   
Our legitimate interests | Being efficient about how we fulfil our legal and contractual duties   
Complying with rules and guidance from regulators.  
To communicate with you to help improve your interactions while using the Service | Identity Data, Contact Data; Marketing and Communications Data,   
Usage Data  
Technical Data | Performance of a contract with you,   
Our legitimate interests | So we can improve our Service provided to you by tailoring the content, to offer customization, and personalized help and instructions that we may send you, and to otherwise improve your experiences.   
  
### SHARING OF YOUR INFORMATION

We will only share Personal Data with others when we are legally permitted to do so. When we share data with others, we put contractual arrangements and security mechanisms in place to protect the data and to comply with our data protection, confidentiality and security standards. 

#### How We May Share Your Personal Data with Third Parties:

  * Affiliates. We may disclose the Personal Data we collect to our Affiliates where necessary for administrative purposes and to provide out Service to you. Their use and disclosure of your Personal Data will be subject compliance with the GDPR. 
  * Vendors. We may disclose the Personal Data we collect from you to third party vendors and service providers who perform functions on our behalf in the normal course of business. Their use and disclosure of your Personal Data will be subject compliance with the GDPR. We will not share your Personal Data with any marketing companies. Each vendor has their own privacy policy. Please refer to our vendor list to see which vendors we will disclose your Personal Data in the normal course of business. 
  * In Response to Legal Process and Regulatory Purposes. We also may disclose Personal Data we collect from you in order to comply with the applicable laws, regulations, judicial proceedings, or other legal processes, such as in response to a court orders or subpoenas or to meet national security or law enforcement requirements and where we believe it is necessary for regulatory reasons. 
  * To Protect Us and Others. We may disclose the Personal Data we collect where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of any agreement between or this Statement, or as evidence in litigation in which IBISWorld is involved. 
  * Processors. We may disclose Personal Data to external service providers who act as processors who provide services to us that are necessary for us to provide the Services. For example, for payment of our services. Their use and disclosure of your Personal Data will be subject compliance with the GDPR. 

#### How We May Share Your Personal Data with Third Counties and International Organizations Outside the European Union:

We are an international organization with our Affiliates located around the world including the United States and Australia. Additionally, we use third parties located outside the European Union (the “EU”) to help us run our business. As a result, Personal Data may be transferred outside the countries where we and our clients are located. This includes countries outside the European Union and to countries that do not have laws that provide specific protection for Personal Data. We have taken steps to ensure all Personal Data is provided with adequate protection and that all transfers of Personal Data outside the European Union are done lawfully and, if you are located in the EU, by your consent. 

### HOW WE STORE AND PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION

We care about the security of your Personal Data and uses commercially reasonable physical, administrative, and technological safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of all information collected through the Service. 

**Storage and Processing:** We strictly protect the security of your Personal Data and honor your choices for its intended use. We carefully protect your data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction. The Personal Data collected through the Service may be stored in the European Union or any other county in which IBISWorld Affiliates maintain facilities, including United States of America and Australia. 

**Protection:** We will maintain appropriate technical and organizational security measures designed to protect your Personal Data from accidental loss, unauthorized use, alteration, or disclosure The Service uses industry standard high encryption security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control and all information is transmitted using Secure Socket Layer (“SSL”) certificates on our web server, giving you the ability to communicate securely with the website server. SSL security makes eavesdropping almost impossible. No credit card details are stored on the IBISWorld server. Although we implement and maintain security measures that are appropriate for our business activities, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable and any transmission of Personal Data is at your own risk. 

**Retention:** If you are not a current client and you have submitted Personal Data, we will store your Personal Data for a period of two (2) years. If you are a client, and you elect to cancel your subscription to our Service, we will store your Personal Data for a period of five (5) years for regulatory reasons. If we process your Personal Data for various purposes, it will be erased automatically or saved in an anonymized manner in which cannot identify you. 

### YOUR CHOICES ABOUT YOUR INFORMATION

Individuals have certain rights over their Personal Data and we are responsible for fulfilling these rights.

#### Access your Personal Data

You have a right to access Personal Data held by us. This right may be exercised by emailing us at data.protection.office@ibisworld.com We will aim to respond to any requests for information promptly, and in any event within the legally required time limits.

#### Amend your Personal Data

To update Personal Data submitted to us, you may email us at [data.protection.office@ibisworld.com](mailto:data.protection.office@ibisworld.com). When practically possible, once we are informed that any Personal Data processed by us is no longer accurate, we will make corrections based on your updated information provided.

#### Withdrawal of your Consent

Where we process Personal Data based on consent, you have a right to withdraw consent at any time. To withdraw consent to our processing of your Personal Data please email us at [data.protection.office@ibisworld.com](mailto:data.protection.office@ibisworld.com) or, to stop receiving a marketing emails from us, please click on the unsubscribe link in the relevant email received from us. 

#### Other Rights including Deletion, Objection & Data Portability

This Privacy Policy is intended to provide information about what Personal Data we collect about you and how it is used. As well as rights of access and amendment referred to above, you may have other rights in relation to the Personal Data we hold, such as a right to erasure/deletion, to restrict or object to our processing of Personal Data and the right to data portability. If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please send an email to [data.protection.office@ibisworld.com](mailto:data.protection.office@ibisworld.com). 

#### Complaints

We will attempt to investigate and promptly resolve any disputes or complaints regarding the interpretation or compliance with this Policy. If you wish to file a complaint about your Personal Data, please send an email with the details of your complaint to [data.protection.office@ibisworld.com](mailto:data.protection.office@ibisworld.com). We will look into and respond to any complaints we receive.

If you are located in the EU, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your habitual residence, place of work or of an alleged infringement of the General Data Protection Regulation.

### HOW WE USE COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGY TO COLLECT INFORMATION

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used by us in order to make the IBISWorld websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to us about visitors use of the IBISWorld websites. Most web browsers allow some control cookies through the browser settings. 

To find out more about cookies, including how we use third party analytics tools, to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, please refer to our Cookie Policy.

### LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES AND SERVICES

Our Services may contain links to third-party websites and these websites are not subject to this Privacy Policy. We have no control of or responsibility for linked websites and provide these links solely for the convenience to you. We encourage you to read the privacy policies on the other websites you visit.

### CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

We are committed to safeguarding our users' online privacy and recognize the importance of protecting the privacy of Personal Data, particularly that of children. IBISWorld takes all required steps to protect the privacy and safety of children in accordance with the GDPR. IBISWorld does not knowingly collect or solicit any information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register as users. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from a child under 13, please contact us at [data.protection.office@ibisworld.com](mailto:data.protection.office@ibisworld.com).

### CHANGES TO POLICY

We reserve the right to amend the Privacy Policy at any time. The date of the last revision to the Privacy Policy will be indicated by the "Effective Date" date at the bottom of this page.

### HOW TO CONTACT US

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or the IBISWorld websites or Service, please contact the us at [data.protection.office@ibisworld.com](mailto:data.protection.office@ibisworld.com).

### AFFILIATES 

The Affiliates are defined as a nominated operator for IBISWorld in the specified country.

  * U.S.A. IBISWorld Inc.
  * U.S.A. ProcurementIQ, a Division of IBISWorld, Inc. 
  * Australia IBISWorld Pty Ltd
  * Indonesia PT. Dataindo Inti Swakarsa
  * UK IBISWorld Ltd

### EFFECTIVE DATE

May 24, 2018   
© IBISWorld 2018
